Seidenberg, Jacob Additional Arbitration Files 5666
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
0000-2999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5666
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Collective labor agreements
5689636
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 18, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 06, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5031 A&B: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5032: Jacob Seidenberg Injunction Study 5175: Jacob Seidenberg Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records 5194: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5229: Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5468: Jacob Seidenberg Arbitration files 5519: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5756: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5773: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5808: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5900: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5935: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5953: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5988: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
Prince George's County (Md.) Board of Education.; Prince George's County (Md.); Seidenberg, Jacob.; Amstar Corporation.; Amtrak.; Associated Press.; Atchison, Topeka and Sante Fe Railroad Company.; Atlantic Y Pacific Tea Company.; Bladensberg, Development Corporation.; Bureau of National Affairs (Arlington, Va.); Burlington Development Corporation.; Celanese Coatings Company.; Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company.; Chicago and Illinois Midland Railway Company.; Chicago, Burlington & Quincy Railroad Company.; ConRail.; Construction Contractors Council, inc.; Crown Cork & Seal Company.; Cuyahoga Valley Railway Company.; David W. Brown, Inc.; Delmarna Power and Light Company.; Eastern Air Lines, inc.; Great Northern Railway Company (U.S.); Hertz Corporation.; Illinois Central Gulf Railroad Company.; IRS National Computer Center.; Kansas City Southern Railway.; Koppers Company.; Lehigh Valley Railroad Company.; Long Island Railroad Company.; Maloney Concrete Company.; Matlack, inc.; Missouri Pacific Railroad Company.; National Airlines; National Education Association of the United States.; Naval Air Rework Facility (U.S.); Newcastle County, Delaware.; Norfolk and Western Railroad Company.; Norfolk Naval Shipyard (U.S.); Owens Corning Fiberglass Corporation.; Penn Central Transportation Company.; Pennsylvania Power & Light Company.; Perfection Garment Company.; Radio Corporation of America.; Reynolds Metals Company.; School of District of Philadelphia, Pa.; Sinai Hospital (Baltimore, Md.); Southern Pacific Transportation Company.; Southern Railway (U.S.); St. Louis Southwestern Railway Company.; Stauffer Chemical Company.; Teamsters Joint Councils. Local 84.; Teamsters Joint Councils. Local 85.; Union Pacific Railroad Company.; United Parcel Service.; United States. Department of Labor.; Virginia Beach (Va.) School Board.; W & L Sloane, inc.; Washington Metropolitan Transit Authority.; Washington Post Company.; Washington, (D.C.) Board of Education of Public Schools.; Western Pacific Railway Company.; Wilson-Sinclair Company.
5689636
- Amstar Corporation; Associated Press; Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe; Atlantic & Pacific Tea Co.; Bladensberg Dev. Corporation; Brovn, David W. Inc.; Bureau of National Affairs; Burlington Devl. Corp.; Celanese Coatings Co. (Box 1)
  - Amalgamated Meat Cutters - Local P-392 - Amstar - AAA - 16 - 30 - 0054 - 73 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Associated Press - United Telegraph Workers (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.1443 Santa Fe - RYA (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Atchison Topeka and Santa Fe RR (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Railroad Yardmasters of America (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A&P Tea Company - Teamsters Local 570 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Transcript and Proceedings (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - David W. Brown, Inc. Carpenter District Council (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Great Northern RR - Transportation Association Employees Union (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - WBNG - BNA AAA 16 30 0169 75 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Celanese Coating Company - AIW - Local 906-FMCS (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Public Law Board no.1099 C+o - BRAC (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Public Law Board no.1742 Clueofo Illinois Midland RR (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Awards - SBA #743 - BRAC - Burlington (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Disputes (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Disputes 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Disputes 3 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Consolidated Rail Corp. (cont.); Construction Contractors Council, Inc.; Crown Cork & Seal Co.; Cuyahoga Valley Railway Co.; Delmarna Power & Light Co.; Eastern Airlines; Great Northern Railroad Co.; Hertz Corporation; Illinois Central Gulf Central Railroad (Box 2)
  - Brotherhood of Railway, Airline and Steamship Clerks (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Construction Contractors Council - Laborers District Council (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Transcript of Proceedings (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Crown Cork Seal - IAM - Local 1672 FMCS 73 KO 11010 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Case #1 Palechka Mr. Seidenberg (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Case #2 Alfano Mr. Seidenberg (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Local 1238 and Delmarva Power and Light (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Manuel A Aponte (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Manuel A Aponte (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Eastern Air Lines - IAM #SBA #635-74 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Eastern Air Lines-IAM (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hertz (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mary Albright vs. IRS National Computer Center (Box 3, Folder 1)
- NRLC (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Koppers co. - IAM - FMCS (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Public Law Board no.1184 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Public Law Board no.1184 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Public Law Board no.1184 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Public Law Board no.1660 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- SBA #196 (Tate) Award #133 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Lonfl Island Railroad Co. (cont.); Maloney Concrete Co.; Maryland, Bd. of Education of Washington Co.; Matlack, Inc.; Missouri Pacific Railroad Co.; National Arilines, Inc.; National Education Association; National Railroad Passenger Corp.; Naval Air Station (Box 4)
  - SBA #196 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Maryland School Administration - Sept. 22-24 A76 Allen City Maryland (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Matlack, Inc. and Petro Construction Tank Line Drivers (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NAL and TWU re: Deborah Smith (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - AAA - CWA (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Public Law Board no.2019, Amtrak (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Public Law Board no.2019, Amtrak (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Naval Air Station - IAM - 39 FMCS 76Ko 5114 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - New Castle county (Del) AFSCME - Local 459 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Norfolk & Western Railway Co.; Norfolk Naval Shipyard; Owens Corning Fiberglass Corp.; Penn Central Transportation Co.; Pennsylvania Power & Light Co.; Perfection Garment Co.; Philadelphia School District; Prince George's County Bd. of Education (Box 5)
  - National Mediation Board Emergency board No. 188 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Emergency Board No. 188 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Owens-Corning Fiberglass - IBT - Local 86 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration Board No. 334 - UTU - PC (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Penn Power and Light Company (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Penn Power and Light Co. Employees Independent (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Perfection Garment Co. - ILGWU (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia School District - Fed of Teachers AAA (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Prince George's County and Prince George's County Board of Education Athletic Coaches (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Prince George's County (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - AFTE Local 241 and RCA (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Reynolds Metals (Aluminum) Printing Pressmen (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - UTU & Commerce (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Arbitration Committee SLSW - UTU (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - UTU Case no.2718 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - UTU Case no.2720 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - UTU Case no.1915 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - UTU Case 1767 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - SBA #100 Awards (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - UTU Case no.1604 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - UTU Case no.1973 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - UTU Case no.1572 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - UTU Case no.1974 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - UTU Case no.1976 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - UTU Case no.1990 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co. (cont.); Sinai hospital; Sloane, W & L, Inc.; Southern Pacific Transportation Co.; Southern Railway Co.; Southern Railway System; Stauffer Chemical Co. (Box 6)
  - UTU Case no.DR-104 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - UTU Case no.2088 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - UTU Case no.1558 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - UTU Case no.1559 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - UTU Case no.1671 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - UTU Case no.1672 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - UTU Case no.1673 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - UTU Case no.1674 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - UTU Case no.1681 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - UTU Case no.1682 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - UTU Case no.DR-124 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - UTU Case no.DR-123 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - UTU Case no.DR-103 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - UTU Case no.DR-126 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - UTU Case no.1405 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - UTU Case no.1602 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - UTU Case no.1948 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Sinai Hospital Inc. National Union of Hospital Care (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - W & J Sloane, Inc. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Special Adjustment Board No. 18 (Train Service Panel) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - SA Board No. 18 (Engine Service Panel) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - SBA No. 857 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Southern Railroad Company (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Public Law Board no.1266 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Arbitration (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Teamsters Joint Councils, #8)4, #85; Union Pacific Railroad Co.; United Parcel Service; United States Dept. of Labor; Virginia Beach School Board; Washington, DC Bd. of Education of Public Schools; Washington Metropolitan Transit Authority (Box 7)
  - McCray Swisher vs. Teamsters (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Public Law Board no.2096 Case No. 8 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.2096 Case No. 13 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - United Parcel - Local 639 - IBT - FMCS (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Docket No. L-76-38 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - VA Beach Teachers Assoc. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - D.C. Public School Washington Teachers Union AAU (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration file No. 76K/06627 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Transcripts (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Public Law Board no.1024 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Public Law Board no.1348 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Public Law Board no.1348 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Wilson & Co. (Briggs) (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Wilson & Co. (Briggs) (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 13)